Guide to the William Graham Sumner Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Writings, 1859-1940; Series II; 43' plus 32 drawers of notecards (77 boxes and 1 folio)
  - Addresses and Lectures
    - Sumner's lectures on "Systematic Societology": notes by Albert Keller, 1899 January-May (Box 67, Folder 1505)
    - Sumner's lectures on Science of Society: notes by A.L. Bishop (AMs), 1902, 1903 February-March (Box 67, Folder 1506-1510)
    - Sumner's lectures on Science of Society: notes by A.L. Bishop (AMs), 1903 March-May (Box 68, Folder 1511-1513)
    - Sumner's lectures on Science of Society: notes by A.L. Bishop (TMs), 1902, 1903 February-May (Box 68, Folder 1514-1531)
    - Sumner's lecture on Mental Reactions: notes by A.L. Bishop (AMs), 1904 March (Box 68, Folder 1532)
    - Sumner's lectures on Natural Rights: notes by A.L. Bishop (AMs), undated (Box 68, Folder 1533)
    - Sumner's lecture on the location and characteristics of various North and Central American Indians: notes by A.L. Bishop (AMs), undated (Box 68, Folder 1534)
  - Notebooks
    - Lecture notes on History 1-9, 1862 (Box 69, Folder 1535)
    - Lecture notes on History 10-17, 1862 (Box 69, Folder 1536)
    - Lecture notes on Meteorology, 1862-1863 (Box 69, Folder 1537)
    - Lecture notes on Astronomy, 1862 November 3-1863 February 24 (Box 69, Folder 1538)
    - "Silliman's lectures" 1-9, 1863 (?) (Box 69, Folder 1539)
    - "Silliman's lectures" 10-16, 1863 (Box 69, Folder 1540)
    - "Silliman's lectures" 18-24, 1863 (Box 69, Folder 1541)
    - "Fisher's Evidence of Christianity", 1863 (Box 69, Folder 1541)
    - Lecture notes on Civil Liberty, 1863 (Box 69, Folder 1542-1543)
    - "Turba Miscellanea", 1860-1863 (?) (Box 69, Folder 1544)
    - Lecture notes on Moral Philosophy, 1860-1863 (?) (Box 69, Folder 1545)
    - Journal, 1863 October 5-1864 May 18, 1864 May 24-October 20 (Box 69, Folder 1546-1547)
    - Notebook on French Studies, 1864 (Box 69, Folder 1548)
    - Notebook on German and French Studies, 1864 (Box 69, Folder 1549)
    - "Etudes sur 1'hebreu", 1864 (Box 69, Folder 1550)
    - Notebook on French Studies, 1863-1864 (?) (Box 69, Folder 1551)
    - "Liber Jesaiae", 1863-1865 (?) (Box 69, Folder 1552)
    - Notebook on Hebrew Grammar, 1863-1865 (?) (Box 69, Folder 1553)
    - Notebook on Hebrew, 1863-1865 (?) (Box 69, Folder 1554-1555)
    - Notebook on Hebrew Grammar, 1863-1865 (?) (Box 69, Folder 1556)
    - Notebook on the value of coins, standard weights, 1865 (Box 70, Folder 1557)
    - Lecture notes on Theology and Philosophy Vol. 1, 1865 (Box 70, Folder 1558)
    - Lecture notes on Theology and Philosophy Vol. 2, 1865 (Box 71, Folder 1559)
    - Lecture notes on Theology and Philosophy Vol. 3, 1865 (Box 71, Folder 1560)
    - Lecture notes on Theology and Philosophy Vol. 4, 1865 (Box 72, Folder 1561)
    - Grade books, 1890-1891 (Box 73, Folder 1562)
    - Notebook with addresses and financial records, 1893-1896 (Box 73, Folder 1563)
    - Grade book, 1893 January-June (Box 73, Folder 1564)
    - Notebook, 1893 January-December (Box 73, Folder 1565)
    - Grade book, 1893 September-1894 June (Box 73, Folder 1566)
    - Notebook, 1894 January-December (Box 73, Folder 1567)
    - Grade book, 1894 September-1895 June (Box 73, Folder 1568)
    - Notebook, 1895-1897 (Box 73, Folder 1569-1571)
    - Grade book, 1896 September-1897 June, 1897 September-Dec, 1897 September-1898 June, 1898 September-1899 June, 1899 September-1900 June, 1900 October-1901 June (Box 73, Folder 1572-1577)
    - Notebook, 1901 March (Box 73, Folder 1578)
    - Grade book, 1901 September-1902 June, 1903 September-1904 June (Box 73, Folder 1579-1580)
    - Notebook, 1904 (Box 74, Folder 1581)
    - Grade book, 1904 September-1905 June, 1905 October-1906 June, 1906 September-1907 June, 1907 September-1908 June (Box 74, Folder 1582-1585)
    - Notebook, 1909 (Box 74, Folder 1586)
    - Grammatical notebook of the Romance Languages, undated (Box 74, Folder 1587)
    - Italian grammar notebook, undated (Box 74, Folder 1588)
    - Notebook entitled "Subjects", undated (Box 74, Folder 1589)
    - Notebook: scattered notes, undated (Box 74, Folder 1590)
    - Notebook on economics, undated (Box 74, Folder 1590a)
    - Notebook of Alfred P. Rockwell, undated (Box 74, Folder 1590b)
  - Subject Files
    - "Election of 1800", undated (Box 75, Folder 1591)
    - "Rotation", undated (Box 75, Folder 1592)
    - "Rise of Democracy", undated (Box 75, Folder 1593)
    - "Jefferson", undated (Box 75, Folder 1594)
    - "Constitutional Amendment", undated (Box 75, Folder 1595)
    - "Assualts on Judiciary", undated (Box 75, Folder 1596)
    - "Economy", undated (Box 75, Folder 1597)
    - "Army and Navy", undated (Box 75, Folder 1598)
    - "Election 1804", undated (Box 75, Folder 1598)
    - "Burr", undated (Box 75, Folder 1599)
    - "Hamilton", undated (Box 75, Folder 1600)
    - "Relations w. Spain", undated (Box 75, Folder 1601)
    - "Further Difficulties w. Spain", undated (Box 75, Folder 1602)
    - "Louisiana and Florida", undated (Box 75, Folder 1603)
    - "Miranda's Exped.", undated (Box 75, Folder 1604)
    - "N.E. Boundary. British debts, convention with England", undated (Box 75, Folder 1605)
    - "Land and Land Speculations", undated (Box 75, Folder 1606)
    - "Commercial War 1806-1812", undated (Box 75, Folder 1607)
    - "Impressment", undated (Box 75, Folder 1608)
    - "Election 1808", undated (Box 75, Folder 1609)
    - "Rise of Democracy to 1812", undated (Box 75, Folder 1610)
    - "Election 1812", undated (Box 75, Folder 1611)
    - "Democracy During War", undated (Box 75, Folder 1612)
    - "The War", undated (Box 75, Folder 1613)
    - "Disunion, HFD Convention", undated (Box 75, Folder 1614)
    - Bibliography on Colonial America, undated (Box 75, Folder 1615)
    - Oregon, undated (Box 76, Folder 1616)
    - Growth of Democracy, undated (Box 76, Folder 1617)
    - 1854 Land, undated (Box 76, Folder 1618)
    - "Filibusters", undated (Box 76, Folder 1619)
    - "Election 1856", undated (Box 76, Folder 1620)
    - "Dred Scott Case", undated (Box 76, Folder 1621)
    - "Social and Economic 1850", undated (Box 76, Folder 1622)
    - "Tariff 1846", undated (Box 76, Folder 1623)
    - "Act 7 June 1836 N.W. corner added to Mo. and so made slave.", undated (Box 76, Folder 1624)
    - "Buchanan's Administration", undated (Box 76, Folder 1625)
    - Democratic Convention: Charleston 1860, undated (Box 76, Folder 1626)
    - "Secession", undated (Box 76, Folder 1627)
    - "Lincoln Message, Constitution of Confederacy, Reconstruction, 1864 Election", undated (Box 76, Folder 1628)
    - Reconstruction, undated (Box 76, Folder 1629)
    - "Election 1872", undated (Box 76, Folder 1630)
    - 1876 Presidential Election, undated (Box 76, Folder 1631)
    - 1800 Election, undated (Box 76, Folder 1632)
    - "State Constitutions", undated (Box 77, Folder 1633)
    - "Proposed Amendments Const. U.S.", undated (Box 77, Folder 1634)
    - "Riots", undated (Box 77, Folder 1635)
    - "Tariff. Votes on 1816-1866", undated (Box 77, Folder 1636)
    - "State and Municipal debts", undated (Box 77, Folder 1637)
    - "Absence from Washington", undated (Box 77, Folder 1638)
    - "Civil Service", undated (Box 77, Folder 1639)
    - "Alabama", undated (Box 77, Folder 1640)
    - "Female Suffrage", undated (Box 77, Folder 1641)
    - "Salary", undated (Box 77, Folder 1642)
    - "Transportation", undated (Box 77, Folder 1643)
    - "Election 1876", undated (Box 77, Folder 1644)
    - "Electoral Count", undated (Box 77, Folder 1645)
    - "Claims", undated (Box 77, Folder 1646)
    - "Land Grants", undated (Box 77, Folder 1647)
    - "Internal Improvements", undated (Box 77, Folder 1648)
    - Reconstruction, undated (Box 77, Folder 1649)
    - Lincoln, Johnson and the Civil Rights Bill, undated (Box 77, Folder 1650)
    - "Adams Admin.", undated (Box 78, Folder 1651)
    - "Usury", undated (Box 78, Folder 1652)
    - "West India Trade", undated (Box 78, Folder 1653)
    - "Inter-State Commerce", undated (Box 78, Folder 1654)
    - "Immigration", undated (Box 78, Folder 1655)
    - "Woolens Bill", undated (Box 78, Folder 1656)
    - "Tariff 1828", undated (Box 78, Folder 1657)
    - "Newspapers", undated (Box 78, Folder 1658)
    - "Government Interference Vaccination", undated (Box 78, Folder 1659)
    - "Panama", undated (Box 78, Folder 1660)
    - "Privileges of Congress", undated (Box 78, Folder 1661)
    - "Municipal Organizations", undated (Box 78, Folder 1662)
    - "Election 1828", undated (Box 78, Folder 1663)
    - "Philadelphia Custom House", undated (Box 78, Folder 1664)
    - "Civil, Social and Economic Circ. 2d war to 1828", undated (Box 78, Folder 1665)
    - "Spoils", undated (Box 78, Folder 1666)
    - "Description of Cabinet. Mrs. Eaton ", undated (Box 78, Folder 1667)
    - "Georgia and the Indians", undated (Box 78, Folder 1668)
    - "Internal Improvements", undated (Box 78, Folder 1669)
    - "Anti-Masons", undated (Box 78, Folder 1670)
    - "Loco Focos.", undated (Box 78, Folder 1671)
    - "Spoliation Payments", undated (Box 78, Folder 1672)
    - "Public Land", undated (Box 78, Folder 1673)
    - "Trade, Manuf., Arts and Sci. 1828-1842.", undated (Box 78, Folder 1674)
    - "Trade, Commerce, and Exch. 1822 to 1832", undated (Box 78, Folder 1675)
    - "Pay of Congress", undated (Box 79, Folder 1676)
    - "Treaty of Ghent", undated (Box 79, Folder 1677)
    - "Election 1876", undated (Box 79, Folder 1678)
    - "Erie Canal", undated (Box 79, Folder 1678a)
    - "Tariff 1820-1824", undated (Box 79, Folder 1679)
    - "Jackson and His Enemies" "Seminole War", undated (Box 79, Folder 1680)
    - "Election 1820", undated (Box 79, Folder 1681)
    - "Privateering", undated (Box 79, Folder 1682)
    - "Navigation Acts", undated (Box 79, Folder 1683)
    - "Army and Navy", undated (Box 79, Folder 1684)
    - "Slavery 1789-1820", undated (Box 79, Folder 1685)
    - "Internal Improvements to 1825", undated (Box 79, Folder 1686)
    - "Era of Good Feeling", undated (Box 79, Folder 1687)
    - "Growth of Democracy, Universal Suffrage, Belief, Liberty", undated (Box 79, Folder 1688)
    - "Missouri Compromise", undated (Box 79, Folder 1689)
    - "Indians 1789-1820", undated (Box 79, Folder 1690)
    - "Tariff 1827", undated (Box 79, Folder 1691)
    - "Caucus", undated (Box 79, Folder 1692)
    - "Election 1824", undated (Box 79, Folder 1693)
    - "The Monroe Doctrine", undated (Box 79, Folder 1694)
    - Jefferson's Inaugural, undated (Box 80, Folder 1695)
    - "Civil Service", undated (Box 80, Folder 1696)
    - "Rotation", undated (Box 80, Folder 1697)
    - "Democratic Sedition Trials", undated (Box 80, Folder 1698)
    - "Revenue Debt and Taxation 1800-1872", undated (Box 80, Folder 1699)
    - The Judiciary, undated (Box 80, Folder 1700)
    - "Constit. Amendment", undated (Box 80, Folder 1701)
    - "Separation of Mississippi Valley Relations with Spain", undated (Box 80, Folder 1702)
    - "Louisiana", undated (Box 80, Folder 1703)
    - "Burr", undated (Box 80, Folder 1704)
    - "Collison Pa. and Fed. Gov.", undated (Box 80, Folder 1705)
    - "Election 1804", undated (Box 80, Folder 1706)
    - Miranda's Expedition, undated (Box 80, Folder 1707)
    - "Election 1808", undated (Box 80, Folder 1708)
    - "Commercial War", undated (Box 80, Folder 1709)
    - "Spoliations", undated (Box 80, Folder 1710)
    - "Growth of Democracy", undated (Box 80, Folder 1711)
    - Fever in Philadelphia 1793, undated (Box 80, Folder 1712)
    - "1796. Great Prosperity in N. Eng.", undated (Box 80, Folder 1713)
    - "Impressment", undated (Box 80, Folder 1714)
    - "British Debts Treaty 1802", undated (Box 80, Folder 1715)
    - Non-Importation, Bonaparte's Continental Policy, Chesapeake, Embargo, Navy, undated (Box 80, Folder 1716)
    - "Civil, Soc. and Econ. Circumstances 1739-1800", undated (Box 80, Folder 1717)
    - The Hartford Convention, undated (Box 80, Folder 1718)
    - "Washington", undated (Box 81, Folder 1719)
    - "Election 1796", undated (Box 81, Folder 1720)
    - "Other Financial Measures", undated (Box 81, Folder 1721)
    - "Formation of parties", undated (Box 81, Folder 1721)
    - "Navigation, Mississippi River, Western Disloyalty", undated (Box 81, Folder 1722)
    - "Minor Dates and Facts, Indians, Immigration", undated (Box 81, Folder 1723)
    - Post Office, undated (Box 81, Folder 1724)
    - Internal Revenues, undated (Box 81, Folder 1725)
    - Fees of Letters Patent Granted by the U.S., undated (Box 81, Folder 1726)
    - "Jay's Treaty", undated (Box 81, Folder 1727)
    - "Neutrality-France", undated (Box 81, Folder 1728)
    - Questions between the United States and Britain, undated (Box 81, Folder 1729)
    - "Whiskey Rebellion", undated (Box 81, Folder 1730)
    - "Results of New Union", undated (Box 81, Folder 1731)
    - "Tariff and Taxes 1789-1796", undated (Box 81, Folder 1732)
    - "Mint and coinage down to 1819", undated (Box 81, Folder 1733)
    - "Debt, Funding and Sinking Fund", undated (Box 81, Folder 1734)
    - "Organization of Government", undated (Box 81, Folder 1735)
    - "Florida", undated (Box 82, Folder 1736)
    - "Tariff", undated (Box 82, Folder 1737)
    - "Economic Notions", undated (Box 82, Folder 1738)
    - "Era of Good Feeling and Growth of Democracy", undated (Box 82, Folder 1739)
    - "Election 1816", undated (Box 82, Folder 1740)
    - "N.Y. Conv. 1821", undated (Box 82, Folder 1741)
    - "Missouri Compromise", undated (Box 82, Folder 1742)
    - "History of the Congressional Caucuses for Nominating President", undated (Box 82, Folder 1743)
    - "The Election of 1824", undated (Box 82, Folder 1744)
    - "Monroe Doctrine", undated (Box 82, Folder 1745)
    - "J. Q. Adams Admin.", undated (Box 82, Folder 1746)
    - "Bankrupt Act", undated (Box 82, Folder 1747)
    - "Panama", undated (Box 82, Folder 1748)
    - "Federal Judiciary", undated (Box 82, Folder 1749)
    - "West India Trade", undated (Box 82, Folder 1750)
    - "Tariff", undated (Box 82, Folder 1751)
    - "Anti-Masonry", undated (Box 82, Folder 1752)
    - "Election of 1828", undated (Box 82, Folder 1753)
    - "American Democracy", undated (Box 82, Folder 1754)
    - "Civil, Social, and Economic Progress 2d War to 1830", undated (Box 82, Folder 1755)
    - "Parties and Politics under Jackson", undated (Box 82, Folder 1756)
    - "Indians", undated (Box 82, Folder 1757)
    - "Internal Improvements", undated (Box 82, Folder 1758)
    - "Lands", undated (Box 82, Folder 1759)
    - Anti-Mason Convention at Baltimore 1831, undated (Box 82, Folder 1760)
    - Destruction of Canals, undated (Box 82, Folder 1761)
    - "Civil and Social - Jackson's Time", undated (Box 82, Folder 1762)
    - "Nullification", undated (Box 82, Folder 1763)
    - "Equal Rights Loco Focos", undated (Box 82, Folder 1764)
    - Andrew Jackson, undated (Box 82, Folder 1765)
    - Letter to A. Gallatin, undated (Box 83, Folder 1766)
    - "Gallatin was not confirmed by Senate as peace Commissioner", undated (Box 83, Folder 1767)
    - "Public Finances 2d War to 1820", undated (Box 83, Folder 1768)
    - Banks, undated (Box 83, Folder 1769)
    - "Banking East 1820-1830", undated (Box 83, Folder 1770)
    - Kentucky - Court Reporting, undated (Box 83, Folder 1771)
    - Bank of the United States, undated (Box 83, Folder 1772)
    - Untitled manuscript on banking pp. 13-30 with notes, undated (Box 83, Folder 1773)
    - Untitled manuscript on banking pp. 31-50 with notes, undated (Box 83, Folder 1774)
    - Untitled manuscript on banking pp. 51-70 with notes, undated (Box 83, Folder 1775)
    - Untitled manuscript on banking, undated (Box 83, Folder 1776-1777)
    - "Public Finances 1815-1820", undated (Box 83, Folder 1778)
    - "Independent Responsibility of Sec. Treas.", undated (Box 83, Folder 1779)
    - "War on the Bank", undated (Box 83, Folder 1780)
    - "Public Finances 1828-1832", undated (Box 83, Folder 1781)
    - Opposition to the Bank of the United States, undated (Box 83, Folder 1782)
    - Bank of the United States, undated (Box 83, Folder 1783)
    - "Fries", undated (Box 83a, Folder 1784)
    - "Papers about Robins Alias Nash", undated (Box 83a, Folder 1785)
    - "Public Finances and Taxation 1796-1800", undated (Box 83a, Folder 1786)
    - "First Embassy to France", undated (Box 83a, Folder 1787)
    - "Difficulties with France", undated (Box 83a, Folder 1788)
    - "Second Embassy", undated (Box 83a, Folder 1789)
    - "Treaty of 1800", undated (Box 83a, Folder 1790)
    - "Quarrel about Army Officers", undated (Box 83a, Folder 1791)
    - "Alien and Sedition Acts Citizen Act, undated (Box 83a, Folder 1792)
    - "Va and Ky Res", undated (Box 83a, Folder 1793)
    - "Judiciary Act", undated (Box 83a, Folder 1794)
    - "Election 1800", undated (Box 83a, Folder 1795)
    - "Breakup of Cabinet", undated (Box 83a, Folder 1796)
    - "Adams Quarrel w. Feds", undated (Box 83a, Folder 1797)
    - Election of 1800, undated (Box 83a, Folder 1798)
    - "Parties at Election 1800", undated (Box 83a, Folder 1799)
    - American Foreign Policy under Adams, undated (Box 83a, Folder 1800)
    - "Coinage 1837-1860", undated (Box 84, Folder 1801)
    - "Election 1852", undated (Box 84, Folder 1802)
    - "Arts, Science, Manuf., Commerce", undated (Box 84, Folder 1803)
    - "Party Politics", undated (Box 84, Folder 1804)
    - "James Polk", undated (Box 84, Folder 1805)
    - "Native Americans", undated (Box 84, Folder 1806)
    - "Slavery - South Aggressions", undated (Box 84, Folder 1807)
    - "Election 1848" (Box 84, Folder 1808)
    - "Slavery. Wilmot Proviso. Admission of California", undated (Box 84, Folder 1809)
    - "Calhoun's New Theories of the Constitution and Slavery", undated (Box 84, Folder 1810)
    - "New York Constitutional Convention and Politics 1846", undated (Box 84, Folder 1811)
    - "Tariff 1846", undated (Box 84, Folder 1812)
    - "Oregon", undated (Box 84, Folder 1813)
    - "National Reformers", undated (Box 84, Folder 1814)
    - "Mexican War", undated (Box 84, Folder 1815)
    - "Post Office", undated (Box 84, Folder 1816)
    - "Polk's Administration", undated (Box 84, Folder 1817)
    - "Election 1844", undated (Box 84, Folder 1818)
    - "Annexation of Texas", undated (Box 84, Folder 1819)
    - "Mexico", undated (Box 84, Folder 1820)
    - "Tyler and the Whigs", undated (Box 84, Folder 1821)
    - "Webster and Tyler", undated (Box 84, Folder 1822)
    - "The Caroline", undated (Box 84, Folder 1823)
    - "North Eastern Boundary", undated (Box 84, Folder 1824)
    - "Tariff 1842", undated (Box 84, Folder 1825)
    - "Internal Improvements", undated (Box 84, Folder 1826)
    - "N.Y. State Politics and Finance", undated (Box 84, Folder 1827)
    - "Distribution", undated (Box 84, Folder 1828)
    - "Rotation 1841", undated (Box 84, Folder 1829)
    - "Repeal Miss. Comp.", undated (Box 85, Folder 1830)
    - "Election 1852", undated (Box 85, Folder 1831)
    - Compromise of 1850 (Box 85, Folder 1832)
    - Texas, undated (Box 85, Folder 1833)
    - "Election 1848 Whig Alliance 1849", undated (Box 85, Folder 1834)
    - "Know Nothing", undated (Box 85, Folder 1835)
    - "Postage Reform", undated (Box 85, Folder 1836)
    - "Polk's Cabinet", undated (Box 85, Folder 1837)
    - "Annexation of Texas", undated (Box 85, Folder 1838)
    - Whig Convention 1844, undated (Box 85, Folder 1839)
    - "Texas", undated (Box 85, Folder 1840)
    - "Apportionment 1842", undated (Box 85, Folder 1841)
    - "MacLeod", undated (Box 85, Folder 1842)
    - "Parties", undated (Box 85, Folder 1843)
    - "North East Boundary", undated (Box 85, Folder 1844)
    - "Door's Rebellion", undated (Box 85, Folder 1845)
    - "Discord in the Administration", undated (Box 85, Folder 1846)
    - "New Administration Extra Session", undated (Box 85, Folder 1847)
    - "Trade and Industry in 1842", undated (Box 85, Folder 1848)
    - "Bankrupt Law", undated (Box 85, Folder 1849)
    - "State of parties", undated (Box 85, Folder 1850)
    - "Election 1836", undated (Box 85, Folder 1851)
    - "Independence and Union", undated (Box 86, Folder 1852)
    - "Wyoming", undated (Box 86, Folder 1853)
    - "The Cincinnati and Tammany", undated (Box 86, Folder 1854)
    - "Internal Weakness of the Confederacy", undated (Box 86, Folder 1855)
    - "Constitutional Convention", undated (Box 86, Folder 1856)
    - "Adoption of the Constitution", undated (Box 86, Folder 1857)
    - "Ratification of Constitution and Rise of Parties", undated (Box 86, Folder 1858)
    - "Doctrine of Democracy", undated (Box 86, Folder 1859)
    - "Organization of Govern.", undated (Box 86, Folder 1860)
    - "Civil, Social, and Economic Status During Confed.", undated (Box 86, Folder 1861)
    - "North West Territory", undated (Box 86, Folder 1862)
    - "War in Europe", undated (Box 86, Folder 1863)
    - "Jay's Treaty", undated (Box 86, Folder 1864)
    - "Formation of parties", undated (Box 86, Folder 1865)
    - "Election of 1796", undated (Box 86, Folder 1866)
    - "Adams Administration", undated (Box 86, Folder 1867)
    - "Election 1796", undated (Box 86, Folder 1868)
    - Presidential Politics 1852, undated (Box 87, Folder 1869)
    - "Know-Nothing-Ism", undated (Box 87, Folder 1870)
    - "Repeal Compromise", undated (Box 87, Folder 1870a)
    - "Kansas", undated (Box 87, Folder 1871)
    - "Slavery Dred Scott Decision", undated (Box 87, Folder 1872)
    - "Charleston Convention", undated (Box 87, Folder 1873)
    - "Treaty w. Mexico 1859", undated (Box 87, Folder 1874)
    - "Secession. Peace Convention", undated (Box 87, Folder 1875)
    - "Constitution Confederate States", undated (Box 87, Folder 1876)
    - "Lincoln's Message", undated (Box 87, Folder 1877)
    - "Military Arrests", undated (Box 87, Folder 1878)
    - "Conscription, Colored Soldiers, Peace Negotiations", undated (Box 87, Folder 1879)
    - "Military Orders Reflecting Elections", undated (Box 87, Folder 1880)
    - "The 'Trend'", undated (Box 87, Folder 1881)
    - "What is a Citizen of the U.S.", undated (Box 87, Folder 1882)
    - "Confiscation", undated (Box 87, Folder 1883)
    - "Emancipation", undated (Box 87, Folder 1884)
    - "Freedmen's Bureau", undated (Box 87, Folder 1885)
    - "Election 1864", undated (Box 87, Folder 1886)
    - "Impeachment", undated (Box 87, Folder 1887)
    - "Tenure of Office", undated (Box 87, Folder 1888)
    - "Resolution of Congress July 22, 1861", undated (Box 87, Folder 1889)
    - "Judic. Decisions", undated (Box 87, Folder 1890)
    - "Election 1868", undated (Box 87, Folder 1891)
    - "Johnson's Message", undated (Box 87, Folder 1892)
    - "Political Platforms 1869-1874", undated (Box 87, Folder 1893)
    - "Election 1874", undated (Box 87, Folder 1894)
    - "Public Land", undated (Box 87, Folder 1895)
    - "Slavery l82(?)-1845", undated (Box 88, Folder 1896)
    - "Campaign 1840", undated (Box 88, Folder 1897)
    - "Panic 1840", undated (Box 88, Folder 1898)
    - "Election 1836" (Box 88, Folder 1899)
    - "Parties, Politics, Political Intrigues", undated (Box 88, Folder 1900)
    - "Nullification", undated (Box 88, Folder 1901)
    - "Election 1832", undated (Box 88, Folder 1902)
    - "Monroe", undated (Box 89, Folder 1903)
    - "Bohemian Oats", undated (Box 89, Folder 1904)
    - "Hawaii", undated (Box 89, Folder 1905)
    - "Carnegie", undated (Box 89, Folder 1906)
    - "N.Y. City Comm. Aqueduct", undated (Box 89, Folder 1907)
    - "Proportional Representation", undated (Box 89, Folder 1908)
    - Taxation, undated (Box 89, Folder 1909)
    - "South - Negro Suffrage", undated (Box 89, Folder 1910)
    - "Napoleon", undated (Box 89, Folder 1911)
    - "Norway", undated (Box 89, Folder 1912)
    - "Bimetallism", undated (Box 89, Folder 1913)